Justin Miranda

https://www.justin-miranda.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/justin-miranda

Orlando, FL • 850-902-6792 • justinmiranda@knights.ucf.edu

SUMMARY:

Computer Science Senior. Very strong background in object-oriented programming. Strong background in full stack development. Background in tutoring programming and math at the collegiate level. Talented in creating my own projects to gain industry experience. Highly skilled at communication and problem solving.

SKILLS:

Programming Languages: C, C++, C#, Java 8, Python 3, JavaScript, HTML 5, SCSS, CSS, Pug

Database: MongoDB, Heroku, Adminer, PostgreSQL, MySQL

IDEs: Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio Community, Eclipse, Android Studio **Frameworks:** Node JS, Express, Mongoose, Flask, SQL Alchemy ORM, Bootstrap

Webserver: Apache

Operating Systems: Windows, iOS, Ubuntu, CentOS, Android

Project Management Software: Github, Perforce

EXPERIENCE:

Programming Tutor

02/2017 - Present

Valencia College

- Sole general programming tutor on Winter Park campus assisting students in best programming practices.
- Tutoring in Python, C, C++, Java, JavaScript, Bash
- Tutoring online via Zoom which used to be face-to-face.
- Assist 1 to 7 students at a time understand arrays, basic algorithms and functions, memory, and pointers.
- Assist 1 to 10 students at a time in Developmental Math, Pre- Algebra, Intermediate Algebra, College Algebra, Calculus I, II, III, Differential Equations, Discrete Math, Statistics and College Math for Non-STEM Majors

Full Stack Developer

06/2020 - 07/2020

Self-Employed

- Environment: Python, Flask, BootStrap, PostgreSQL, Adminer, Heroku, HTML, and CSS.
- Created and designed a book rating platform that takes APIs from goodreads.com for the values of the ratings and reviews then presents them for users to assess.
- Users can register, login, logout, search books within the database, review books, and rate books.
- Implemented a python program that uploaded 5000 comma-separated books to the Heroku database.

Game Developer

05/2020 - 06/2020

Self-Employed

- Environment: Unity, VS Code, C#, Audacity
- Project involving a 2-D platformer rocket game that allows users to control its flight.
- Programmed the controls and level success/failure events.
- Created prefab objects for faster level creation.
- Wrote and recorded the music.

Backend Development Mango Greenhouse 01/2020 - 04/2020

- Environment: Node.js, JavaScript, VS Code, React, MongoDB, Express.js
- Involved in a group project developing a web and mobile application that would give users the temperature, humidity, and UV light indices for their personal greenhouse.
- Created the backend APIs in JavaScript for the web application that synched with a Particle iO board which posted information on current conditions to act as a greenhouse application.
- API development with async functions utilizing Express and MongoDB Management with Mongoose.

EDUCATION

University of Central Florida – Orlando, FL GPA 2.93 **01/2018 - 05/2021**Bachelor of Science Degree in Computer Science, Minor in Secure Computing And Networks (SCAN)

Relevant Courses

• Processes of Object-Oriented Software, Cyber Security, Cryptography, Comp Sci I & II, System Software, Discrete I & II, Java & C Programming and many more.

08/2017

Valencia College – Orlando, FL Associate of Arts Degree in Computer Science

REFERENCES

Pasha Utt

VP Java Developer Team Lead at Citi

uttpasha@gmail.com

Lisa Keeton

Valencia College Tutor Manager

lkeeton@valenciacollege.edu